

Vasilika Klimova

Developer Advocate

I have been speaking at conferences, helping different communities and teaching people web basics since 2015. I like to share my knowledge and motivate others. I'm interested in making products more desirable, understandable and usable.

I gave more than 20 speeches, was a guest on several podcasts, and hosted different webinars and workshops as a Frontend Expert.

Skills



Achievements

Google Developer Expert

In Web technologies since 2022

Interests



Visited about 30 countries



Contact

- ★ Luxembourg
- **4** +352 661 101 603
- ≥ 2607lika@gmail.com
- **in** Likita
- ♥ @Lik04ka
- **O** Likita
- 🔾 vasilika.ru

Experience

Avalog

Business and Technical Consultant | 2018 - Present

FinTech company. I am mainly doing Frontend. Work with small and very big Angular applications. Creating Angular libs and web components. Responsive markup, client customisation. CI & CD. A mentor for Juniors.

<u>Stack</u>: Angular, Angular Material, RxJS, Web Components, OpenShift, Sass, Jenkins,

Swagger, Postman, YAML, AngularJS.

Artec3D

Frontend Team Lead | 2013 - 2018

3D scanners. I was responsible for a Frontend team. Involved in a lot of meetings with design approvement. Created different websites: 2 CRM, 3D models shop and viewer, landing pages. Server-side rendering with Node.js. Functionality for the 3D viewer. Testing with Capybara / Selenium / Poltergeist. A project with a QML interface. Getting feedback from CRM users. CI & CD. Hired a team.

<u>Stack</u>: React, Redux, JavaScript, Webpack, CoffeeScript, HAML, Sass, Stylus, Three.js.

Varna

Full-stack Programmer | 2011 - 2012 Online game portal.

Creation of game portals with a social network. <u>Stack</u>: PHP, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, HTML, CSS.

Morozko

Web Master | 2010 - 2011

Retail sales. A huge supermarket.

Design and markup of e-commerce and corporate websites. Creation of admin panel. SEO. Team management (3 people). Stack: PHP, MySQL, HTML, CSS, CMS.

Education

Master in Engineering and Technology in the field of Information Technology and Computer Science

Tver State Technical University, Tver | 2006 - 2012

Graduated with Honors degree

Own Projects

SkillUp School in Luxembourg

Founder, Teacher | 2019 - Present

I teach adults and children without any IT background web basics and mentor them.

Cute Geek IT Agency

Founder, Manager | 2019 - Present

We do different web projects for clients. I know how to deal with clients' requirements and, at the same time, motivate a development team.

<u>Stack</u>: React, Node.js, PHP, SQL, Three.js, e-commerce, Gulp, CMS: WordPress, Joomla, Drupal.

Additional activities

Co-organiser Luxembourg JS community, 2019 – Present

- Search for speakers & meetup venues, speech rehearsals, MC, and a Speaker. More than 10 online and offline meetups and after parties.
- Co-organiser Frontend Union Conf, 2015

I was responsible for all social nets, announcements and public communication.

Co-organiser Moscow JS community, 2015 – 2017

Search for speakers & meetup venues, speech rehearsals, MC, and a Speaker. We did more than 20 events for 2 years.